《异形魔怪2：余震》
小惹火 你如不自己走进栏
Wildfire, you either walk into that other corral,
我会打死你将你的尸体拖进去
or I am going to shoot you and drag your carcass in there.
来吧 小惹火 来吧 乖孩子
Come on, Wildfire. Come on, boy.
现在让我们一起去找苏丝吧
Let's go meet Susie now.
你会喜欢它的
You will like her.
你俩要好好相处
You two got to get together.
捉到你啦
Gotcha. Whoa, whoa. Whoa,
站住 该死
boy, whoa. Whoa. Damn it.
现在 你和苏丝要造些小鸟来
You and Susie are going to make some little birds,
如果不是 我就烤了你们
or I'm gonna take some barbecue sauce to both of you.
你是爱尔·巴锡 对吗？
Earl Basset, right?
我告诉你 那是另外一个
I told you that's the other one.
巴锡先生…
Senor Basset.
这是个美丽但孤立的城市
This is beautiful country, but very isolated.
我花了很多气力才找到你
I had great difficulty finding you,
很高兴我的心血并没白费
but I am glad I did.
你见到吗？
You see,
我们关闭了墨西哥最大的油田
we have had to close down one of Mexico's biggest oil fields.
好些工人被杀死
Several workers have been killed.
我们发现那些工人是被…
Ah, we have now determined that…
某些巨大 地下生物所杀
the men were killed by… certain large underground animals.
加博怪虫？
Graboids.
啊 人们就是这样叫它们的
Ah. I told you that's what they named them. Excuse me.
你是否说 有很多这类生物？
You mean… there's more of them?
是 公司正面对最昂贵的停工
Yes. The company is facing very expensive delays.
但最重要的是
But more importantly,
这区的居民大部份孤立自处
there are many isolated people who live in the region.
每个生命都受威胁
Many lives are in danger.
我们急需专家们去歼灭那怪物
We need someone, an expert, to eliminate these creatures.
你想找人去捕捉加博怪虫？
You want somebody to go graboid hunting?
是
Si.
先生 请听我说
Ah, senor, please, please.
我们已和你的拍挡麦基谈过
We have already spoken to your partner, Senor McKee.
他不愿意加入协助
He… he is unwilling to help us.
当然啦 他婚姻生活愉快
Sure, Val married a good woman.
为何他会去寻死？
Why would he want to die?
当然 我们愿意付出任何数目
Of course, we are willing to pay.
当然 他们愿意付出任何代价
Of course they're willing to pay.
好啦…五万元
Fifty thousand…
废话
Go… away.
不是这个意思
No, no, no.
我愿意付每只加博五万大元
He wants to pay you $50, 000 for each graboid.
很动听 不答应 我不会为任何数目加入
Look. No way. Not for any amount of money.
但对你来说
But for you,
对付那些虫只简直易如反掌
getting those worms would be a piece of cake.
你是谁 为何你那么蠢钝？
Who are you? And why are you so dumb?
我是加迪何化
Oh, Grady. Grady. Grady Hoover.
好荣幸认识你 巴锡先生 我应是你最大拥护者
It's an honor to meet you, Mr. Basset, sir. I am probably your biggest fan.
那个利薄球鞋广告
That Reebok commercial with you guys
你一班人跑步跨沙漠 好帅
running through the desert… so very cool.
你喜欢那个广告？
You like that, huh?
噢 十分喜欢
Oh, yeah.
我可否进来数分钟呢？
Listen, could I come in? I mean, just for a second.
可以
Great.
谢谢
Thanks.
独一无二的爱尔·巴锡
The Earl Basset.
噢
Oh
我读过每个关于这些的故事
Yep. I have read every one of these.
这个我有两个复制品
I got two copies of this one.
我将其中一个用塑纸包着
I keep one wrapped in plastic.
噢我的天 你也有一个
Oh, my God, you got your own one of these.
噢 我相信这些令你赚了不少
Oh, I bet you made a fortune off this.
钱呀 钱呀 钱呀
Quarter, quarter, quarter, quarter.
其他人做的 当然不是我
Well, somebody did. It sure wasn't me.
那么 你一家有分一份利润
Well, you must have got a percentage.
我早该聘用一位律师
I should have got a lawyer.
哇 那太不幸了
Wow… That sucks.
他真的愿意付五万元一只？
Did he really say $50, 000?
我发誓 绝无虚假
Stack of Bibles.
还是算了
Forget it.
你们不知那些东西多恐怖
You boys don't know how mean these things are.
那好吧 但… 那是我的大好机会
Well, okay… okay, but… That was my big chance.
是啊 但是巴锡先生…
Yeah, but M-Mr. Basset…
你只有一只 但都给我搅坏了
You only get one of those in life, and I blew it…
都是那坏蛋大鸟和它瘦弱女伴
on goddamn Big Bird and his scrawny girlfriend.
是啊 但五万大元嘛
Yeah, but 50, 000.
那正是她在上面的原因？
That's what she's doing there.
谁？
Who?
谁？1974年十月小姐？
Ooh."Miss October, 1974"?
正是她 她整天都在提醒我
Yeah, she's there to remind me
不要费力追求得不到的东西
not to keep chasing after things I am never going to get.
但你又为何不去捉那些怪虫？
But why wouldn't you get this?
爱尔？巴锡先生 你是位专家
Earl… Mr. Basset, you're the expert.
你们经常和这些东西搏斗
You guys kicked ass with those things.
同时这次你们比它们更胜一筹
And this time, you will be a step ahead of them.
他说墨西哥会供给你任何你想要的
He said the Mexican army is willing to give you whatever you want.
炸药 机枪 好多五万大元
Dynamite. Shh, whoo, wa-bam. 50 Gs.
或者这次是你的第二次良机
Maybe this is your big second chance.
奥蒂加先生 我们就合作吧
Senor Ortega, you have got a deal.
太好了 太好了
Bravo, bravo.
我是否与他一起去呢？
And I am going with him.
很好 很好 但这是不行的
Ah, muy bien, muy bien. Um, if you will excuse me?
什么？为何我长途跋涉到这里
What? Why do you think I drove all this way?
当他说他要找寻爱尔·巴锡
When he said he was looking for the Earl Basset,
我知我的机会来了
I knew Opportunity
第一时间 我便来到这处
was knocking, and I was home.
但我们素未谋面
I don't even know you.
我是做的士司机 我家居破屋
I drive a taxi, I live in a crappy apartment,
我看太多电视 等等 等等
I watch too much TV, et cetera.
想清楚 你将需要一个拍挡
Look, you're going to need a partner.
有多少人愿意做这危险工作
How many people would want to do this?
我会为你做所有的事情
I will do anything you want:
背你的行李 煮咖啡 点火等
Carry luggage, make coffee, light fuses.
唔 或都你也有用得着的时候
Maybe you will come in handy.
当那些虫吞食你的时候
Ha. When they're eating you,
我便可乘机逃脱
it will give me a chance to get away.
看 谁拿了最后一罐汽水？
Who gets the last soda?
一 二…
One, two…
什么？
What?
包 剪 踏 一 二 三
Scissors, rock, paper. One, two, three.
这是什么？
What's this?
较剪剪纸 我赢
Scissors cuts paper. I win.
你好 先生
Buenos dias, senores.
你就是去打怪物的那个美国人
Ustedes dos son los americanos cazadores de monstruos? Um…
请问…
Um… Quien es… uh…
不是…
No, no, no, no.
奥蒂加先生在哪里？
"Donde esta…" Senor Ortega?
奥蒂加？呀 奥蒂加 你好
Ortega? Oh, Ortega, venga aca. Estan aqui.
欢迎各位 你们来得正好
Welcome. Welcome, gentlemen. You made good time.
我们早些来到 就可早些走
The sooner we get here, the sooner we can leave.
这是本公司工程师-毕度
This is Pedro, the company's chief engineer. Mucho gusto.
很高兴认识你
Uh, buenos dias. Ysu nuevo companero, el
你好
Sr. Hoover.
还有他的新朋友 何化先生
Mucho gusto. Buena suerte y que los monstruos no los coman a ustedes.
你所需的装备都在那里
Um, I have all your equipment over here.
顺便告诉你一个好消息
Oh, by the way, I have some good news.
如果你们能活捉一只怪虫
We offer you double the price
你们得到的酬劳是双倍计
if you are able to capture one of the animals alive.
双倍？
Double?
活捉？你有没有见过那些怪虫？
Alive? Have you ever seen one of these things?
那只不过是一个建议而已
It is only a suggestion…
如果能活捉一只就最理想了
if it was possible to capture one of them.
事情未发生 你永不知道结果
No, you never know.
爱尔…你永不知道
Earl, you never know.
我当然知道结果应如何？
Yes, I do.
那就是我不应来到这处
Never should have come down here.
墨军已将你要求的一切送到
The army has sent everything you requested.
你要求了一些不寻常的东西
You have asked for some… Unusual things.
呵呵 爱尔 来看这些东西
Earl, please check this out.
听着 不要将这事看得太儿戏
Look, this isn't some kind of party.
我知道 我只想注进多些热情
I know that. I just think we should show a little enthusiasm here.
让我介绍姬.利莉给你认识
Let me introduce you to Kate Riley.
她是本油公司的地质学家
She's the geologist for the oil company.
他们是…
And these are the men…
我知…我知他们是怪虫猎者
I know, I know. The monster hunters.
我在早晨美利坚见过你们
I saw you on Good Morning, America… or, uh, one of those.
这是爱尔·巴锡 独一无二的
Yeah, this is, uh, the Earl Basset, the one and only.
说得对 很高兴认识你
Uh, that's right. Nice to meet you.
很高兴认识你
Really nice to meet you.
我是新成员加迪·何化
I am Grady Hoover, the new guy.
是吗？
Nice…
好漂亮的帽子
hat. Thanks.
各位
Gentlemen
希望你们很快会送来好消息
I hope to hear good news soon.
利莉小姐负责与我保持联络
Miss Riley will stay in contact with me.
如果有任何需要 请告知我
Let us know anything else you need. And, uh…
那么 祝各位好运 愿主常在
Well, best of luck to you, huh? Vaya con Dios.
好吧 这就是你们的居所
So this is the place.
我会带你们到四周逛一逛
I will show you around.
你们想喝些什么东西吗？
You thirsty or anything?
事实上 我很口渴
Yeah, as a matter of fact, I am.
其实在这区的人都很慌张
Anyway, we have been pretty nervous down here.
幸好你们长途跋涉都到这里来
Glad you guys were willing to come all this way.
这里确是荒芜之地 鲜有人迹
It sure is in the middle of nowhere. Well, of course.
当然 怪诞的事都在荒野发生
Stuff like this only happens in the middle of nowhere.
喂 朱利奥
Hey, Julio.
喂 姬
Hey, Kate.
怎么样… 全部做妥 他们正在工作
So? It's all done. They're all working. Yes, yes.
很好 各位 这是朱利奥
Guys, this is Julio.
他就是为我们装置地震仪的人
He's been setting up the seismographs.
这是爱尔·巴锡
Earl, Grady.
对 我在报刊上全见过你们
Yes, I have seen you in the magazines.
事实上 我不是正版队员
Actually, I am not the original guy.
你们一定赚很多金钱 对吗？
You know, you must have made a lot of money, huh?
单是那电视游戏机 的版权….哇
The royalties on that video game alone. Ooh.
朱利奥 我们现在应有
Julio, we should be able to
正确的数地震方法 对吗？
get an accurate count now, right?
对 你知我朋友投资在这公司
Yes, yes. I have a friend who invested in that company.
喂
Hey.
噢 你好 请进来
Hi. Come on in.
我们是否要查看一些地图呢？
So, uh, we were going to look over some maps?
对 唔…咖啡？
Right. Um, coffee?
好的 黑咖啡
Yeah, black.
那些墨西哥薄饼如何？
How were those burritos, anyway?
唔…还好 还好
Um, good. Good.
很不好意思 我知道簿饼味道差
Yeah, sorry about that.
我知道很糟 但厨师跑了 那已是最好的了
Pretty bad, I know. But with cook gone, that's best we have got.
呀 有多少人仍然在外面工作
So, um… how many of you are still working out here?
唔…只有我们三人 公司要将工场关闭
Only the three of us. They had to shut the whole operation down.
因有六人被杀 全部我都认识
Six people got killed… people I knew.
为什么你还待在这里工作？
Hmm. Well, uh, how come you stayed on? Well…
难道你不害怕吗？
You're not scared?
我当然十分害怕
Shit, yeah, I am scared.
但同时对这事极感兴趣
But… I am also fascinated. It's, uh…
对我来说 兴趣胜于一切
With me, "fascinated" usually wins.
地图…
Maps.
我会将那些核心拿走
I will get these cores out of the way.
来吧 宝贝
Come on, baby.
其实加博怪虫有否靠近炼渍油厂
So, uh, have the graboids come near the refinery yet?
没有 至今它们还没靠进附近
No, they have left us alone.
它们大都在北面二十公里外出没
They stay about 20 miles north.
工人就在那处遇害
That's where the workers were killed.
其实 谁始创加博这名字呢？
Who named them graboids, anyway?
张华特 我们的一个朋友
A… friend of ours, Walter Chang.
张为它们起名 而它们吃了他
He named them, then they ate him.
各位 看我做了什么出来
Hey, guys, look what I made.
只要把它拖在货车后面
Just, you know, drag it behind the truck.
它就会发生更巨大的声响
Make, you know, make more noise. Just…
知吗 加博怪虫是声音捕食
You see, uh, graboids hunt by sound.
我立刻把它挂在货车后面
I will probably just go hook that to the back of the truck.
难以置信
"Moonstros."
是的
Ah, si.
何化先生 请过来
Mr. Hoover, come here please.
我不断用监察器侦察
I have the monitor working.
我们将电子地震仪放在每角落
We have set up radio seismographs all over,
- 我地震仪上有波动便是加博所在 - 棒
- so the monitor will show you where the graboids are. - Cool.
虽然我这样问有点多管闲事
You know, this is none of my business, I guess,
但我想知队伍是否只你一人
but you guys are going out there alone?
你们有否考虑带整队墨西哥去
You don't want to take with you the whole army of Mexico?
朱利奥 让我解释给你听
Let me explain, Julio.
加博怪虫是没有眼睛的
Graboids, they got no eyes.
它们依靠声音捕食
They hunt by sound.
如你弄出轻微如脚步声 它们都可发现你
You make a noise. They're going to come after you.
现在 若找一群人在这里走动
If we get a bunch of people running around…
加博便汹涌而至
Graboids going to spread out all over the place.
我们要加博只过来找我们
No, we want them all to come to us.
那么 你们算是什么？
So you guys are what?
你们是鱼饵吗？
You guys are the bait?
这根本就是我们的计划
That's the plan.
好
Okay, so, uh…
全部人齐集 货车在那
That's us. That's our truck.
看来每样都进行得很顺利
Seems like everything's working okay.
当然顺利啦 爱尔
Well, sure it is, Earl.
这是高科技 专业化的行动
This is a high-tech, professional operation here.
喂 我们拥有一个完美计划
Hey, we got a good plan going.
五万大元一只 宝贝 哇
Fifty thousand apiece, baby.
你知我怎么样去捉我的加博？
Ho. You know, me, I am going to get mine all at once,
全部堆在一起
just stacked.
如果我再赚到钱
Well, if I make any money this time,
我会很保守地去投资
I will invest it… conservatively.
喂 你剃须没有？
Hey, you shaved.
什么？
What?
没有 我发现你没剃须
No, I just… I just noticed you… you know, shaved.
那又怎么样？每个男人都懂剃须
So what? A man can shave, can't he?
是 你说得对 她是个弱女子
No, you're right. She's a babe.
好吧
Well,
它们应在这里出没
here's where they're supposed to be.
噢 欣赏一下这个城市 什么？
Man, look at that country, huh?
对 并没有太多的石头岩石
Yeah. Not a lot of rocks and boulders out there.
确实没有什么可攀爬
Not much to climb on if we don't want to get slurped.
这里四周有很多山峰
There's mountains around.
你说它们不能攀越山峰
You said they can't get through mountains.
我曾说过它们不能穿越岩石
I said they can't go through rock.
但这些山丘是沙石冲积而成
These hills are alluvial.
冲积土？等下
Oh, "alluvial." Wait a minute,
那不就是你的忧虑吗？
that's the little dingleberry in the back of your throat, right?
如想捕捉加博
You want to hunt graboids,
你最好对地质学有认识
you better know geology.
来 你驾驶 我看着这地震仪
Here, you drive. I am keeping my eye on this… seismo-jigger.
噢 好
Oh, good call.
我没有恶意 爱尔
No offence, Earl,
但你为何惊慌得如一只小狗
but you're nervous as a chihuahua.
我不是紧张 只是保持警觉
I am not nervous. I am alert.
你怎说怎好
Whatever.
如那些怪虫没听到我们的尖叫
Those worms have to be deaf
它们就真的聋的厉害
if they don't hear us.
喂 轻松一点
Hey, take it easy, huh?
天呀 加迪 一只出现了
Jesus, Grady. We got one.
它看到我们啦 它朝我们走过来
It's spotted us. It's coming right toward us.
这正是我们的目的
Well, that's the idea.
我知这是我们的目的
I know that's that's the idea.
但并不表示我要去欢迎这景况
Doesn't mean I have to like it.
现在 停止 你可否停下来？
Now stop. Stop already.
好啦 秘密武器表演时间到了
Okay, time for the secret weapon.
小心那雷管 按照我教导你的方法装置
Careful with that detonator. Set it like I showed you.
你认为我很蠢吗？
How dumb do you think I am?
稍后才告诉我吧
Catch me later on that one.
他来了 我相信他在跟踪它
He's coming in. I think he's following it.
它肯定是
Of course he is.
我看不到它 爱尔
I can't see it, Earl.
爱尔 我看不到它
Earl, I can't see it.
左 爱尔左 左
Left. Left. Left.
- 好 好 - 等下 在这
- Okay, okay. - Wait. Wait, there.
他成功啦 他捉到它
He did it. He took it.
好 打它 打它 捉住它
O-Okay. Hit it. Get him.
爱尔 你在做什么？
Oh, shit. Earl, what are you doing?
打它 打它 打它 爱尔
Hit it. Hit it, Earl.
哈哈哈 五万元 宝贝
Whoo-hoo-hoo. 50 Gs, baby, 50 Gs.
五万大元
Oh, shit.
早告诉过你
Told you.
我忘记了
I forgot.
喂 这东西真的极臭
Man, this stuff really stinks.
不要忘记连触须也带走
Yeah, don't forget to get that antenna too.
你留下收音机在地上？
You left the radio on the ground?
对不起…我忘记了
Sorry, I forgot.
那是只豺狼吗？
Is that a coyote?
是
Yep.
它最好不要作声
Man, he better keep quiet.
是
Yep.
- 它捉了它 - 喂 轮到我了
- He took it. - Hey, it's my turn.
噢 来吧 爱尔 给我打多一只 不好
Oh, c-come on, Earl. Let me get one more. Shit.
踏破剪 我赢
Rock breaks scissors. I win.
是吗？
It does?
早告诉你一击便足够
I told you one stick would be enough.
你对
You're right.
那便有三十万元了
That makes $300, 000.
一只
Apiece.
噢 我太聪明了 爱尔
I am feeling light-headed, Earl.
你打算怎么样花这些酬劳？ 投资
And what are you going to do with all your money?
是 当然 投资 但…
Invest it. Well, yeah, of course, invest it, but…
纵只有五厘回报 已是好收入
Even at five percent, I will be doing pretty good.
五厘？你是说公债或定期或…？
Five percent? You're talking, um, mutual funds or CD's or something, huh?
正是 那太少了 爱尔 你思想太保守
That's right. That's small, Earl. You're thinking small.
而我 我想有一番作为
See, I am thinking big, okay?
好像…
I am thinking…
建游乐场 那…
theme park. Now, now.
何化生态世界
"Grady Hoover's World of Natural Wonders."
哇 或者简单
Whoa. Or, you know, maybe something simple,
如怪兽世界
like "Monster World", or "Monsterland"…
或者怪物乐园
or "Worm World."
叫做卡通世界乐园好吗？
How about "Looney World"?
很合衬 走离地面
Seems to fit. Get off the ground.
那是有远见 爱尔
It's vision, Earl.
远见是分开平凡的界线…
Vision is what separates the average…
我懂那首歌曲
I know that song.
天 离开地面 加迪 离开地面
Jesus. Get off the ground, Grady. Get off the ground.
天 那些东西真是巨大
Jesus, man, those things are huge.
不要作声 你有没有看见那张嘴？
Shh. Be quiet. Did you see that mouth?
不好 它挣开那铁链
Oh, no. It snagged the chain.
它能这样吗？
Can it do that?
它不该这样强壮
It can't be that strong.
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch.
快踏刹车擎
Hit the brakes.
我有 我有
I am. I did.
但它失灵
It doesn't work.
我应做什么？
Earl. What do I do?
- 我什么也不知道 - 噢
- I don't know. Do anything. - Ooh.
- 卡里夫 - 不要
- Cliff. - Oh, no.
它停下来 它停下来
He stopped. He stopped.
噢 不好
Oh, shit.
来吧
Oh, come on.
石头
Rock. Rock.
它由底部穿过
He's going under it.
转…转那轮子 转
Turn. Turn the wheel.
- 转 - 我正在尝试转 我正在尝试
- Turn. - I am trying, I am trying.
噢 我的天
Oh, God, oh, God.
你没事吧？
All right.
You all right?
哇 铁链断了
Wow, chain broke right off.
上帝 我们走运
Jesus, we're lucky.
看 货车好像没损坏
Well, truck seems to be all right.
爱尔 那将是我游乐场的首程
Earl, that's going to be the first ride in my theme park.
没有任何东西令你受挫吗？
Doesn't anything ever get you down?
上天赐给我一个开朗的性格
Well, I am blessed with a sunny disposition.
非常受人们欢迎
Most people seem to like it.
是吗 这对你的开朗有何帮助
Oh, yeah? What does this do for your disposition?
我相信我们需要援手
I think we're going to need some help.
援手？在这混乱的情景
Help? Who'd be crazy enough
有谁会走来帮忙？
to help us with this mess?
你是？
Yeah?
喂 毕…
Hey, Burt,
我是爱尔 你好吗？
it's Earl. How you doing?
听住
Listen, um,
如果这听来有些古怪 因为我用广播电话
If this sounds kind of funny, it's because I am on a radio phone.
这是我唯一可与你联络的方法
It's the only way we can call out of this place.
爱尔？呀爱尔 很久没见
Earl? Oh… Earl. Haven't seen you in a while.
我也很久没见你
Well, I haven't seen you.
我想你近来一定很休闲 对吗？
Guess you have been laying kind of low, huh?
休闲？错 我才忙得要紧
Laying low? No. Negative.
很多大工程等着我
I have been real busy… lots of projects.
你和希达都好吗？
So, uh, how you and Heather doing?
她…她还在她姐姐处
Well, she, uh… She's still visiting her sister.
真的？
Yeah?
基本上 她将我们之间的问题
You know, she actually…
都推御在苏联崩溃所导至
blames our problems on the collapse of the Soviet Union?
那你都忍住气 毕
Well, you did take that kind of hard, Burt.
她说我很难相处
Said I was hard to live with.
又说 没世界大战的威胁我没法活
said I couldn't handle life without the threat of war.
这样的说话怎么可对男子汉说
What kind of thing is that to say to a man?
我都不知道 毕
Well, I don't know, Burt…
不过 是其它东西才令我低落
Anyway, it takes more than that to get me down.
我整天四处跑
I been running around so much,
你能在家中找到我还算幸运
it's lucky you caught me home.
这么 不知你对这事有没兴趣
Well, in that case, I don't know if you'd be interested in this.
我现身处墨西哥 看…
I am down in Mexico, see,
我觉得自己处于很为难的境况
and I find myself in a sort of situation.
你处于什么困境？
What kind of situation?
是加博怪虫的问题
A graboid kind of situation.
喂 你负责监察那荧光幕？
Hey, you keeping an eye on that monitor?
是我负责 它们还停留于北方
Uh, yeah, I am watching it. They're just staying up north.
- 噢 我的天 - 什么事？
- Oh, my God. - What?
对不起 你来 你来 看这处
Come here. Come here. Look at this.
我在月前对这化石已进行研究
I have been staring at this fossil for over a month,
我今天才知道这是什么来的
and I just realized what it is.
爱尔 那好像它们的长尖简
Hey, Earl, that looks like one of those spikes on their sides.
是 非常相似
Okay, it resembles one.
我想一定是 我很肯定
I think it is. I really think it is
是加博的化石碎片
a fossil fragment of a graboid.
我才知需要多月来去证明这一切
It's going to take months to prove…
不 不…
No
这是很重要的 对吗
his is important, isn't it?
科学永没法断定它们的来源
Science has never determined their origin.
我曾在人民杂志读到这
I read that in People.
很正确 但那不是唯一的东西
And that's true. But that's not the only thing.
这是全金比因石
You guys, this is Precambrian rock.
金比因
Precambrian…
意即比地球还要早出现的生物
That means that this is the oldest life form on the planet.
我的意思是 除了单细胞生物
I mean other than one-celled things.
但 看看这
But look at that.
- 等一下 是否比恐龙还古老 - 绝对是
- Wait a minute. Older than dinosaurs? - Way.
那么 它们是在地球上繁衍 是的
So they're from earth, right? Yeah. Damn.
噢 我还以为它们从外星来
I always thought they were from outer space.
一点也不是
Doesn't look like it.
看 看 那好大啊
Mira, mira. El monstruo mas grande… viene aca.
看…看
Look. Look at the seismograph. Look.
看那体积 很巨大啊
El monstruo viene. Es grande.
那并不是加博
It ain't no graboid.
定是比加博还危险的东西
It's something more dangerous.
我怀疑这是总部吗？
Monster H.Q., I presume.
- 毕 见到你真好 - 爱尔 见到你真好
- Hey, Burt, good to see you. - Earl, good to see you.
这是姬
Uh, this is Kate, uh,
毕度 你好
Pedro, Hey, what's up?
- 朱利奥 荣幸 - 荣幸
- Julio, and, uh… - The pleasure is mine. Grady.
加迪·何化
Grady Hoover.
我全认识你们 金玛先生
Yeah, I read all about you, Mr… Mr. Gummer.
- 真是很大的荣幸 - 是的
- Yeah, it's a real… real honor. - Yes.
还以为你的货车够宽大呢？
Man, you think you got a big enough truck here?
他是新丁？
He the new guy?
你有否带地震仪来
So, did you get me one of those seismo-monitors?
没有问题 喂 你在哪里得到这个东西？
Hey, no problem. What you got in this thing?
喂 喂
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
不要触摸 不准触摸
Don't touch. Don't touch. Easy.
那很容易 墨西哥军送来货车
Mexican army gave me this truck…
同时还送来其它我要求的东西
And a few little items on my wish list.
那太过份了 你认为是吗？
It's, uh, a bit much, don't you think?
或者是我错…
Maybe I am wrong.
但希望我是对的
Hope I am right.
令我自制的火药沦落为爆竹
Makes my home-made stuff look like cherry bombs.
撒姆炸药 G-4 全顶级炸药
Thermite, C-4, TNT, high-explosive… H.E.
世上有没有低爆炸性的东西呢
Is there such thing as "low-explosive"?
有 小孩 当然有
Well, y-yes, son, there is.
墨军军官有求必应
I mean, the federales offer you anything you want,
你们只拿了一箱炸药？
and you guys take one case of dynamite?
到底那些要来作什么？
What the hell is this thing for?
可能成为我的收藏品
That, uh, might end up in my collection.
各位 为你们带来一些新产品
Hey, got some, uh, new equipment for you, gentlemen.
你的后备武器 你能运用吗？
Your backup weapons. Can you handle a firearm?
让我看一看
I will check him out.
猎枪？
Shotguns?
我们并非去打小兔子呀 毕
We're not hunting rabbits down here, Burt.
并非猎枪 这里有双响炮
Not shotguns. Double rifles. Elephant guns.
象枪 480型李察威斯利
Wesley-Richards 480,
375H麦
375 HandH Mag.
全部具有强大的毁坏力
Knockdown power up the yin-yang.
好好对待它们
Treat them well.
但用它们时记紧紧贴你的肩部
But hold them good night to your shoulder,
如没贴紧你的锁骨 便很容易被打碎
or they will break your collarbone.
那金玛太太在哪里？
So where's, uh, Mrs. Gummer?
她不想参加吗？
She didn't want to come?
呃…你拿着这个吧
Uh, why don't you get this,
在我们货车上的东西
uh, stuff in our truck?
好 没问题
Sure, no problem.
各位 我很感谢你们来到这里
Look, man, I… really want to thank you for coming down.
我们的处境并非乐观
We're in pretty deep here.
不要这样说 爱尔
Oh, forget it, Earl.
老实告诉你 如不出来做些事
To tell you the truth, if I didn't get out of that house,
我想我一定发疯
I was going to go crazy.
希达不会回到我身边了
Heather's not coming back.
不会？
No?
她叫我把她的HK-9枪寄给她
She called me and told me to send her the H.K. 91.
很不妙
Whew. Ouch.
好吧
So.
无论如何
Anyway,
不如做些有建设性的事情
it will be good to get into something constructive.
天 这是什么？
Oh, my. What is this?
加士利单步枪 五十口径步枪
Grizzly single-shot 50-calibre B.M.G…
全基于世界大战的爆炸性仿制
based on a World War I
而造成的子弹
antitank cartridge.
反坦克？那些子弹全部人手用铜制成的
Antitank? Had the bullets custom cast from solid bronze.
毕 你为超级杀伤力注入新意
Man, Burt, you put a whole new shine on the word "overkill."
当你需要它 但又没在手上
When you need it and don't have it,
那你的说法就不一样
you sing a different tune.
就这样了吧 毕 好
Well, this is it, Burt. Okay.
我去东面视察 你去西面
I will patrol east. You take the west.
你知那些怪虫十分恐怖
You know, those are terrible for you.
你需吸收大量炭水化合物
You need complex carbohydrates.
但请降低你的胆固醇
Lower those LDL's.
我已戒烟了 毕
I already gave up smoking, Burt.
你还要我怎么样？
What more do you want?
- 食个快餐 - 食什么？
- Have an M.R.E. - A what?
快餐 急冻 锡纸保鲜
Meals Ready to Eat. Freeze-dried, foil sealed.
只先锡纸保装 保鲜纸易坏
It's got to be foil. Plastic is not an oxygen barrier.
快餐包括 主菜 饼干 芝士
Includes entree, cracker pack, cheese spread,
杂果 饮料粉 汤匙 咖啡
mixed fruit, beverage powder, spoon, coffee,
奶粉 糖果 盐 火柴和面纸
cream substitute, candy, salt, matches, toilet tissue.
可储藏十年
Shelf life of ten years.
来 拿一些
Here, take a few.
我时常去买 省得去超级市场
Buy them all the time. Saves trips to the supermarket.
不用客气 毕
Oh, no, Burt.
- 不好意思吃你的食物 - 没问题
- We don't want to use up all your food. - No problem.
我买了一百二十磅
Brought 120 pounds of it.
祝你好运 朋友们
Good luck, compadres.
这些好像厕纸那样难吃
Oh, man, this stuff tastes like toilet paper.
爱尔 那才是厕纸
Earl, that is the toilet paper.
十四号 五月… 1500小时
14 May. 1500 hours.
我有很确定加博所在的指数
I have a confirmed graboid reading.
我正运用爱尔·巴锡
I am now employing the technique pioneered by Earl Basset…
传授的技俩去发出我的第一炮
to make my first kill.
目标已受饵
Subject has taken the bait.
准备发炮
Preparing to fire.
记录…
Memo:
四磅C-4可能…
Four pounds of C-4 may be a little…
太多
excessive.
喂 加迪 爱尔
Yo, Grady and Earl.
我打到一只 完毕
I got one. Over.
知道了 毕
Yeah, we know, Burt.
我们听得很清楚
We heard it clear over here.
这是只极可恶的东西
Damnedest thing.
有条大铁链从它的口中垂下来
It had a big chain hanging out of its mouth.
毕 你卑鄙 那只是我们的
Damn it. Burt, you skunk, that one was ours.
是吗 小孩？
Oh, yeah, son?
我看不见有你的名字
I didn't see your name on it.
通话 结束
Over and out.
为何我们邀请他加入？
Why did we invite him, anyway?
喂 留神呀
Hey, pay attention.
哈 我看到一只 等一下
Whoa. We got one. Wait a minute.
它远离我们
It's moving away from us.
一定是其它东西
It must be something else.
是什么？巨大的牧场狗？
Like what, a giant prairie dog?
呃 我不知道 爱尔 它正远离我们
Well, shit, I don't know, Earl. It's moving away from us.
要跟踪它吗？
Should we follow it?
到底它是怎么搞的？
What the hell is the matter with him?
我们已发出这么大的噪音
We're making plenty of noise.
太不好了 加迪
I don't like it, Grady.
它们变得很聪明 它们学乖了
They're getting smarter. That's what they do.
它们一定在进行某些计划
They got some kind of plan going here.
我告诉你
I tell you,
它们一定有新计划
these boys are up to something new.
掘陷阱等我们
They're digging a trap for us, or…
或者…装死
playing possum.
一定不会简单
Or something.
圣母保佑
Holy Mother.
噢天 噢天 噢天
Oh, man, oh, man.
蠢蛋 为何我会这样做？
Shit. Shit, how could I do that?
要去拿毕的枪
I got to get to Burt's gun.
它在哪里？它应该在附近才对
Where is he? Should be all over us.
我不知道
I don't know.
- 那是什么？是它们做的吗？- 嘘
- What is that? Can they do that? - Shh.
我也不知道
That's a new one on me.
上帝 加迪
Jesus, Grady,
你在做什么？快离开地面
what are you doing? Get off the ground.
知道 知道 我有个主意
I know, I know. I got an idea.
信任我
Trust me.
不要 加油 快回来
Damn it, Grady, come on back.
它仍在
He's still there.
它到底在做什么？
What the hell's it doing?
不知道
I have no idea.
这东西有些不妥
Something's wrong with him.
一定是生病
Must be sick.
或者它吃了的人令它肠胃不适
Probably ate somebody that didn't agree with it.
上帝 加迪
Jesus, Grady.
没事 爱尔
It's okay, Earl.
它不会去别处
He's not going anywhere.
喂
Hey.
我们刚活捉一只
We just caught ourselves a live one.
那是十万元 爱尔
That's $100, 000, Earl.
- 棒 - 是吗？你想怎么样？背它回来？
- Oh, yes. - Oh, yeah? What're you going to do, carry him back?
我们的货车刚毁坏了
We just wrecked the truck.
真的
Oh, yeah.
喂 这边是爱尔 有人在吗？
Hello, this is Earl to anybody. Anybody there?
爱尔 我是姬 你们怎么样了
Hey, Earl, it's Kate. How're you guys doing?
我们受到了一点撞击
we kind of wrecked our truck a little bit.
什么？你没事吧？
What? A-Are you okay?
没事 不过我们需要人到这里接应
We're fine. We're going to need somebody to come fetch us.
等下
Just for a sec.
等一下 请叫毕度驶他的旧货车来接应
Look, would you tell Pedro to bring that big old truck of his out here?
有一座吊臂在货车上 对吗？
It's got a crane on it, doesn't it?
是
Yeah.
但他要很久才能到
It's going to take him hours to get there.
无论如何 叫他驶过来
Tell him to bring it out here because…
才能运它到邪恶世界
We're going to winch that slinky off to Monster World.
请即闭嘴 同时立即离开地面
Get off the damn ground.
我立即离开 马上走开
I am off. I am off.
上帝
Jesus…
可恶 他得到另外一只
Damn it, he got himself another one.
永不见那人睡觉
The man never sleeps.
各位 这是毕 我仍在搜罗
Guys, Burt here, doing a little night fishing.
这里有三只聚在一起
Got three of them on a cluster charge.
看来我们大家打个平手
I'd say we're about even now. Over.
来吧 毕 这并不是场比赛
Come on, Burt. This isn't a competition.
谁人在比试？
Who's competing?
我只是说大家得个平分而已
I am just saying the score's tied, that's all. Over.
朋友 我们活捉了一只
well son, no it isn't, because we just caught ourselves a live one.
你感受如何？
How about that?
生擒？那怎么会发…
A live one? How in the…
唔 那是小小的商业秘密 狩猎愉快 毕
That's a trade secret. Happy hunting, Burt.
我肯定那令到他很气恼
I will bet that burned his skinny ass.
全能上帝
God Almighty.
我们的小虫有些不妥当 爱尔
Something's wrong with our worm, Earl.
你想我怎么样？
Well, what do you want me to do about it?
或者有其它的东西
Maybe something's trying
想吃了它 可能是野狼吧？
to eat it out there… coyotes or something.
它们有很多东西可吃 对吗？
They will have plenty to eat.
来吧 爱尔
Come on, Earl.
我们快保护我们投资品
We have got to protect our investment.
不可只坐在这里
We can't just sit here.
天 仔细听
Jesus, listen to it.
可怜 其实 你有否可怜它？
Poor thing. I mean, don't you just feel a little sorry for him?
没有
No
那太冷血了 爱尔
That's cold, Earl.
那个毕度在何处 那坏货车呢
Where's that Pedro and that damn truck?
某些东西…吃了它
Something ate it.
只两分钟？
In two minutes?
一定有事发生
Well, something happened to it,
因为里面什么都没有
because there is nothing left inside.
有东西从里面跑出来
Something came out of it.
什么意思 有什么跑出来？
What do you mean, something came out of it?
对 有一种动物是这样变身
It did that thing that things do when they change, you know…
有一句话来形容的
there's a word for it, uh…
那会变成不同的
It turned into something else
好像毛虫变蝴蝶那样
like a caterpillar does.
无论它变成什么东西
Only I bet that whatever came out
一定不会是美丽的蝴蝶
wasn't no sweet little butterfly.
那死虫永不令人轻松一点
Damn worms never cut you any slack.
我说我认为你应跑去里奥华地
I said I think you all ought to head out to Rioverde.
直到我们知道这是什么事情
Clear out until we know what's going on. Over.
通话 姬？那东西有否出现？
Kate, did you get any of that? Over.
通话 可恶 又怎么了？
Shit. Now, what?
通话器坏了 怎么会这样？
The radio's out. How could that be?
刚才我还与她讲话
I was just talking to her.
喂…你知那是什么 对吗？
Man. You know what that is, don't you?
对 另外一只正做同样的事情
Yeah. Another one's doing it.
看 毕度在那里
There. There's Pedro.
差不多是时候
About damn time.
他停下来
He stopped.
He stopped?
或者他正在小便
Maybe he's taking a leak?
那小便真久
That's a long leak.
喂 毕度 毕度
Hey, Pedro. Pedro.
好吧
Well
或者我们要走去看个究竟
maybe we should go over and see what's wrong.
走过去？你说在荒野上走一里
Go over? You mean, walk a mile across open country?
我不离开这地震仪超过六尺
I am not going six feet from that seismo.
来吧 我们附近肯定没有加博
Come on. There's no graboids anywhere near us right now.
过去一定没有事发生
Now, I say we go while the going's good.
你可携带一些这物品
You know, you could carry some of this stuff.
我已拥有我想要的
I got what I want.
我不能说很好 毕度？
Well, I can't say this looks good.
毕度
Pedro?
喂 毕度
Hey, Pedro.
带来了旧回忆
This brings back memories.
好像有人拿罐头刀去那东西处
Jesus. Looks like somebody took a can opener to the thing.
不妙…看看那引擎
Oh, man. Look at that engine.
全部粉碎
It's torn to pieces.
毕度
Pedro.
可恶 你在哪？喂
Damn it. Where are you?
他在这儿
Hey. There he is.
毕度…？
Pedro?
喔 天啊
Oh, God. Oh, God.
这是个全新的游戏
It's a whole new ball game.
崭新的游戏
A whole new goddamn ball game.
你知应怎么样做 是吗？
Well… Well, you know what to do, right?
对吗？我全不知
Right? I don't know shit.
好…好
Okay. Okay.
我们可步行到讯号塔
We can hike over to that radio tower.
他们定有好的通话机
Th-Th-They have got to have a radio that's working.
我可直接致电去
We can, uh… We can call direct.
十四号 五月 黄昏十时
14 May. 1900 hours.
已数小时不能使用通讯机
I have been out of radio contact for several hours,
无法联络到加迪和爱尔
unable to reach Grady and Earl
或在总部的人 照情况看
or anybody at H.Q.
我非要返回基地不可
The situation dictates that I return to base.
更进一步的谜
A further mystery:
已有数小时没有测量记录
I have not had a single seismic reading in hours,
但我是追踪着加博来到这山谷
yet I tracked one of the sightless brutes right into this valley.
到底它去了哪里？
Where the hell did he go?
它们真的变得聪明
They do get smarter.
它真能
Is it possible he learned…
辨别我货物的引擎声？
to avoid the unique sound of my deuce-and-half's mil-spec engine?
我也没法解答这问题
I do not have the answer at this time.
不要 不要 不要…
Oh, no, no, no.
不要告诉我又是通讯机事故
Don't tell me that's the radio stuff.
我不可以相信这
I can't believe this.
天…我们能否好运些
Oh, man. Can't we ever get a goddamn break?
如果我们能活着离开这地
If we get out of here alive,
我们已非常幸运
I will count that as a break.
其实 这地方并没有人类可吃
I mean, there wasn't even any people here to eat.
它们这样做一定有目的
They're doing this on purpose, man.
它们有目的地令我们孤立无援
They're cutting us off on purpose.
静 静点…
Shh. Shh. Quiet. Quiet.
我已告知你它们变得很聪明
I told you they get smarter.
喂 看
Hey… look.
是的 我们不会有车匙
Oh, yes. Yes. It's not going to have a key.
- 即是说我要想办法推动引擎 - 正合我意
- So I will hot-wire the damn thing. - I like that.
加迪 加迪
Grady. Grady.
什么事？
What is that?
我不知道 但它正朝这边走来
I don't know, but it's coming this way.
上帝 那东西有多大？
Jesus. How big is this thing?
那是什么？
What the hell is that?
是它吗？
Is that it?
肯定不是只驼鸟
Sure ain't no damn ostrich.
一个三十尺大的虫
How does a 30-foot worm
怎么会变成如此细小呢？
turn into that little thing?
静 它可能听到
Shh. Might hear us.
不好 它听到了
Shit. It heard us.
等一下
Wait.
捉到它了 捉到它了
We got it. We got it.
丑陋的癞虾蟆
Ugly little toad.
没眼睛
No eyes.
哇 好像那些大的
Wow. Just like the big ones.
爱尔 可…
Earl, man.
我们定要带走这只
We ought to take this one with us.
你疯了吗？ 为什么？
You crazy? What?
好像有很多这些东西
Sounds like a bunch of them.
来吧 朋友…我们走吧
Come on, man. Let's go. Let's go.
我在尝试 我在尝试
I am trying. I am trying.
我们走吧
Let's go.
毕度 你听到我吗？
Pedro. Can you hear me?
爱尔 来吧…
Earl, come on. Talk to me.
和我通话 毕？
Burt? Anybody?
到底发生了什么事？
God. What the hell is going on?
- 噢…噢 - 嘿
- Oh, man. - Hey.
- 朱利奥 你吓得我半死 - 对不起
- Julio, man, you scared me half to death. - Sorry.
靠
Oh, shit.
你知那些通讯机 全坏了？
You know the radios… They're out?
我知道 我正在抢救
I know. That's what I have been doing here.
我想通讯塔可能坏了
I think the repeater towers are down.
那怎么会呢？
How can that be?
我不清楚
I don't know.
有东西朝我们这边来？
Something coming our way?
不 那些生物在荧幕上全消失
No. The creatures have completely disappeared off the screen.
很奇怪
It's weird.
如果通讯机全坏了
With the radios all out,
那全部人不是要回来吗？
shouldn't everybody come back?
对呀 全部人早应全部撤回
Yeah, everybody should have been here a long time ago.
我不喜欢这样 这样不好
I don't like this. This is not good.
好…姬 你守着地震仪
Okay, stay here with the seismos.
我现在就出去找他们
I am going to go look for them right now.
噢 噢 我的天 我的天
Okay, but…oh oh oh
救他 救他
Get him. Get him.
畜生
Bastards.
姬…
Kate.
那是什？那是什么？
What are they?
我们也不知
We don't know.
那些怪虫不知怎么的蜕变了
The worms change somehow.
现在又有这些东西出现
Now we have got these things.
朱利奥…朱利奥…
Julio. Julio. They… They…
我知 我知
I know. I know.
但我们打败它们
We got them, though.
我们刚轰走它们
We just blew them away.
毕度 毕度有否找到你？
Pedro. Did Pedro find you?
没有 他们发动他的货车
No. They jumped his truck.
毕度已身亡
He's dead too.
你有没有看见毕？他回来了吗
Have you seen Burt? Did he get back?
没有 我尝试与他通话
No. I tried to call him.
- 我又试过与你通话 那通讯机 - 哦 不好意思
- I tried you. The radio… - Uh, excuse me.
我们要立即出发
But I think we should get going.
- 你没事吧？- 你无恙吧 没事
- You okay? - Uh-huh. Yeah.
噢 不要 不要
Oh, no. Not again.
它们搞坏了我们的车子
They wrecked our car,
毕度的货车 通讯塔
Pedro's truck, the radio tower.
为何它们会那么聪明？
How can they be so smart?
我们快走进去？
Let's get our butts inside.
我们要做什么才好？
What the hell we going to do?
首先 关掉所有窗口
Get these windows shut.
它们对这事好像全有计划
It's like they got the whole thing planned.
加迪…加迪 来吧
Grady. Grady. Come on.
好 你认为它们数目有多少？
All right. How many do you think there are?
好 我记得…
All right, I remember. I remember.
我记得有三个大袋
There was three big sacks, or bags,
或者那些袋子裂开缝 爱尔？
in that one we saw split open. Huh, Earl?
在怪虫的肚子里
Can't be more than three of those things
应不会超过三只那些异形
in each worm.
我估计 你说得对
Yeah, I… I… That's right, I guess.
姬 外面还剩下多少只怪虫？
Kate, how many big worms were left out there?
你只杀死八只加博 我很留神地监察着
You killed all but eight graboids. I was watching.
如果那八只全部蜕变
So if all eight of them changed,
那有…
that would make, uh…
二十四只
Twenty-four.
那剩下二十四只异形
Twenty-four of those things left.
你杀死多少只？
How many have you killed?
我想想…唔
Well, let's see…
在讯号塔杀死一只 外面一只
We, uh… We killed one on the radio tower and…and one out there…
还有 唔…
and, um,
一只在车顶
one top of the car.
就那么多？
That's it?
很惭愧
Well, I am sorry.
噢 不妙… 那么 我意思是…
No. It's just that I mean…
喂 又是什么？
Oh, man. Now what?
感谢上天 是毕
Thank God, it's Burt.
好 他没被杀死
Yes. They didn't get him.
我还以为他死了
I think they did get him.
毕？毕…？
Burt.
你没事吧 毕？
Burt, you okay? Burt?
我觉得有人蓄意
I feel I was denied…
把最重要的基本资料隐瞒
critical, need-to-know information.
我们也不想 毕
Well, we're sorry, Burt.
它们的生态突然全改变
They just changed all of a sudden, man.
本应我们可警告你
We would have warned you,
但它们将通讯塔毁坏了
but they knocked out the radio tower.
到底 毕 发生了什么事？
Come on, Burt. What happened?
当线路断了
Well, when the radios went out,
我决定返练油厂
I decided to return to the refinery.
中途上 我觉得四击有埋伏
But en route, I find I am in an ambush situation.
相信有数十只那些怪物
Must have been a couple of dozen of these things.
那我即运用半自动机枪
I dropped the first wave with semi auto fire,
但它们始终不断侵入进来
but they just kept coming.
幸运地 它们大都在货车前面
Most were in front of the truck,
我便用货车辗过它们
so I popped it in six-wheel and ran them down.
其中一只侵入车内 我便随机应变
The ones that got on board, I handled with a combination…
用了近身武器
of small arms fire and hand-to-hand techniques.
那真吓坏了我
I am completely out of ammo.
同样的事不要再发生在我身上
That's never happened to me before.
可恶…谁会理会 毕
Well, shit. Who cares, Burt?
好像你把它们全部杀清 是吗
Sounds like you killed them all, huh?
我希望没有 这些生物很重要
I hope not. These creatures are very important.
我意思是 在科学上来说
You know, I mean scientifically.
我不能忘记刚发生的一切
That fact was not lost on me.
事后 我见一只小杂种吓呆了
When it was all over, I saw one of the little SOB's was just stunned.
我便捉住它
So I detained him.
天 你在胡说
Oh, man, it's drooling.
你不要被吓坏
Don't let him spook you.
同时对自己的说话要负责
That line is 1, 000-pound test.
去吧 把它拖上来
Go on. Haul him out of there.
我早知道 红外线
I knew it. Infrared.
那异形怪物并不真正看到人
It doesn't hear us. It doesn't actually see us.
它们利用触角去探测人类体热
It senses the heat of our bodies.
看那…那升起的东西？
See that? The thing that rises
一定是探测热度的触角
up must be the heat sensor.
哇 感觉到吗？
You feel that?
当他吼叫时会发出大量热气
Gives off a lot of heat when it screams.
就是我相信它们靠这通讯
That's it. I bet that's the way they communicate.
声音是无关重要的
The sound doesn't matter.
即是 它们虽发出声音
They make noise,
但它们靠体热互转消息
but they signal each other with their body heat.
它们只探测到热量？
It only sees heat?
对 那也不太怪诞
Yes, that's not so weird.
响尾蛇就是热度袭击的
A rattlesnake strikes at body heat.
那就是它们毁坏汽车的原因 因为引擎热
That's why they tore up the cars… because the engines were hot.
它们以为是食物
They thought it was food.
通讯塔同一道理
And the same thing with the radio tower.
那些电子齿轮发出各样的热气
That electronic gear puts off all kinds of heat.
基本上 它们吃所有暖的东西
So basically, they bite anything that's warm.
你在说 它们表现得很智慧
They been acting so smart
其实是因为它们很愚蠢？
because they're so stupid?
但 那不暖
Now, that's not warm.
它又为何懂得去吃它呢？
How does he know to eat that?
它用舌头试味道
Well, it tastes it with its tongue.
你没看见它整天拖着舌头走
See how he's dragging his tongue all over.
如果它碰到喜欢的东西
Touches anything he likes, uh,
它就吃
he eats it.
它有多大食量？
How much can he eat?
那些快餐并不便宜 你知吗
Those MRE's aren't cheap, you know.
看来它已吃饱了
Looks like he's had enough.
你喂它太多 你令它感到不适
You're feeding it too much. You made it sick.
放过我吧
Give me a break.
是你的食物令它不适才对
Probably your nasty food made it sick.
噢 仁慈上帝
Oh, good God.
雌雄同体
Hermaphrodites.
它们不需异性去繁殖
They reproduce without having sex.
我先要小的
I claim the little one.
等一下 那是我的食物
Hey, wait a minute, it was my food.
当它们吃饱肚子
Whenever one of them gets enough food,
它们就…另外一只就出来 然后
they just bla-a-ah, and there's another one. And then
一化二 二化四
one makes two, two makes four, four
四化八 那指数学
makes eight… it's exponential.
该死…
Well, uh, hell.
那对它们很有利
That gives them quite an edge.
在高等动物中没有这情况
You never see this in higher animals.
从来没有 很令人震惊
ever. It's astounding.
你们明白吗？
Don't you guys get it?
明白 我们只是不想去想它
Oh, we get it. We just don't want it.
我想那小的已变大了
The little one's getting big already.
是时候来计划离开这处
Uh, I think we better think about leaving.
这些怪物有他自己一套进化论
These guys have taken a completely different evolutionary path.
它们吃了你的特级食物 爱尔
They got into your damn super-food, Burt.
货仓 我们要关好货仓 噢
The warehouse. We got to close the warehouse. Oh…
- 这边 - 加迪 不
- This way. - Grady. No.
加迪 不 不 非这样 加迪
No. Not that way. Grady.
- 加迪 可恶 那是行不通的 - 好 好
- Grady, damn it.. This isn't going to work. - All right. All right
可恶
Shit.
它们停了下来 它们在兜圈子
They stopped. They're just milling around.
- 它们好像追踪不到我们 - 对 但…这不会持久
- Looks like they lost track of us. - That's not going to last.
我们正坐以待弊
We're like sitting ducks here.
抱歉 我觉得那像座大楼
Well, it looked like a goddamn building.
你为何不听我的话？
Why didn't you listen to me?
来吧 那些蠢东西又盲又聋
These little snappers are blind and deaf.
我们一定有办法收拾他们
We have got to be able to beat them.
我早告诉你它们看不见我们
I told you, they can't see us.
太好 现在又做什么？
Great, now what?
跟随着我移动
Now, move with me.
移动？
Move?
那会成功的 可恶
It's going to work, damn it.
立即动身 一步…
Now move. And step,
一步…一步
and step and step…
我不知你怎么想出这鬼主意
I don't know how you come up with this shit.
我有我做事方法 看 见效了
I think on my feet. Come on. It's working.
跟着你
Coming at you.
那 我们去哪儿？
So… where are we going?
还有没有汽车剩下？
Are there any more cars left?
唔…唔…有
Um, uh, yeah.
一辆 朱利奥的
One. Julio's.
它在
It's
储藏柜旁
by the storage tank.
哪个方向？
Which way?
左…左
Left. Move left.
好 预备动 左
Okay. Ready and moving left,
一步…一步 一步
and step, and step, and step,
一步…
and step and step.
好 不用再走 停住
Okay, it's not much further.
天杀的
Oh… damn…
外面有一只异形
Goddamn, there's one of them out there.
它可看见你吗？
Oh, shit. Did it see you?
我不清楚
I don't know.
如果它看见 我们早已知道了
Well, if it had, I think we'd be hearing about it by now.
有多远？
How far is it?
一…一…一百码左右
Uh, uh, 100 yards about.
真差劲的枪法
That's a heck of a shot.
哇 你只打一枪
Whoa. Whoa. You got only one shot?
那你快把它打死
Then you got to hit it, man…
迟些它把所有兄弟全召来
before it sends one of those heat signals to the others.
知道
I know.
掩住他的耳朵
Cover your ears.
天
Jesus.
上帝
God.
连它的屁股也打不到
You smoked his ass.
- 我已在有限的资源做得最好 - 棒
- Doing what I can with what I got. - Good.
不要 打开篷子
Oh, no. Pop the hood.
知道 知道
I got it, I got it.
可恶
Damn.
我们死定了
We're dead.
什么？我不知道 我怎么知道？
What? I didn't know. How could I have known?
我们理应去打击加博嘛
We're supposed to be up against graboids.
我想极度渗入
I wanted maximum penetration.
你成功了
Well, you have got it.
接下来怎么样？
Now what?
此地不宜久留 我们最好进去
We can't stay here. We have got to get inside.
呀…呀 食物部
Uh, Cantina.
可恶
Damn.
毕 毕
Burt?
毕
Uh-oh. Burt.
不要 毕
Oh, no, Burt.
毕 那方法见效了…
Burt, it's working.
它们不能找到你 不要动
They can't find you. Don't move.
好 好主意
Good…Good idea.
这真可怜
This is pathetic.
等一下 我有主意 或者
Wait a minute. I have got a plan, I think.
爱尔
Earl. Earl.
我明白 给我多一分钟
Yeah, I know. I know. I just need another second.
呀 呀 可恶 哎呀
Ow. Ow. Shit. Ouch.
太美妙了 噢这里…这里
That's great. Uh, here. Here.
准备随时冲出去
Get ready to run.
- 我们要跑去爬上油塔 - 好
- We're going to head for those oil towers and climb. - Okay.
是 爱尔 你是个天才
Yes. Earl, you're a genius.
这很清楚 赶快
Come on. It's clear. Hurry.
好了 它们不懂爬
You're okay. They can't climb.
- 注意你的脚 - 噢
- Watch your shin. - Oh, man.
好狡猾 朋友
They can't climb. Pretty slick, my man.
狡猾？那太智慧了
Slick? That was brilliant.
- 天 你不是用脑袋思考 对吗 - 嗯
- You really do think on your feet, don't you? - Yeah, well.
毕在哪里？
Hey, where's Burt?
在那边 请不用担心
Oh, over here. And don't worry,
它们不会找到毕的
they can't even find him in there.
他应该很安全
Oh, man. I think he's going to be okay for now.
我真一流 我们现在怎么做？
Oh, I am just dandy. So what do we do now?
毕
Hey, Burt.
你肯定你没有多些子弹？
Are you sure you don't have any more bullets?
你有否察看所有的口袋？
Did you check all your pockets?
我躺在这处 不能不提出意见
You know, as I lie here, I can't help but comment.
我消耗了几个强力子弹的原因
The reason I am out of nine millimeter
是因为没有人正确地教导我
rounds is I was not properly briefed.
还有另一个原因
And the reason for that is this
是因为这任务没有好好地筹备
mission was not properly researched.
如果有人能事前
If certain people had bothered to gather intelligence on the creatures…
去做准备功夫
before bumbling into the situation…
不要再说毕
Knock it off, Burt.
我们不会在这里用这大废物
We wouldn't be down here with single shot…
没人叫你来
Nobody made you come.
而我们应该用全自动机枪
When we should be packing full-auto, preferably belt-fed.
住口
Shut up…
它们是金拜恩类史前生物 毕
They're Precambrian life forms.
那有人去搜集这类资料呢？
How's anybody supposed to research Precambrian life?
那有什么不同？
What difference does it make now?
我们被困在那屋顶与那些
We're stuck on a goddamn roof with
上堆想吃我们的不知名生物
a bunch of whatsits trying to eat us.
我以前也试过 我不喜欢这样
I have done this before, and I did not like it.
好…那全是我的错
Okay. It's all my fault.
事情全不如我们预料
So things didn't work out exactly the way we planned.
如有适当的工具 我定成功
If I had the right tools, I'd finish the job.
天 你们可否轻松一点？
Jeez. Would you just all relax?
看 自昨晚起我们便与外隔绝
Now, look. Nobody's heard from us since last night,
那么人们就会来拯救 对吗？
which means pretty soon they're going to be up here looking for us, right?
现在我们需静心等待
So all we have to do is sit and wait.
好吗？
ok?
毕？
Burt?
我想我应该去学西班牙语
So I figured I wanted to learn some Spanish,
那么在墨西哥六个月会很受用
and six months in Mexico would be an adventure.
呀…看见其他人吗？
So, uh…Seeing anybody?
自从那怪物来到便没有
Not since the monsters arrived.
你知道
Well, you know, you…
在这里待数天便差点遇害
spend a couple of days almost getting killed, you start, uh,
相信你也会想想自己的将来
thinking about your future and…
是否觉得对
Thinking you should date more?
事实上
Well, uh, yeah, actually.
在这情况下 我未见过有女人
Uh, look, uh, I just don't meet that many women who can
可保持那么冷静
keep their cool…
在这情况下
in a situation like this.
我不介意
What I mean is that, uh…
女人可否应付
What matters to me is that a woman can handle herself.
我只在乎她表现出来的型像
It's much more important than what she looks like.
很多谢你
Thanks a lot.
其实 你很漂亮
Aw, come on. You look great.
- 有没有足够的男人告诉你这？- 嗯
- Enough guys have told you that. - Yeah, well.
不相信也好 我曾当过模特儿
Believe it or not, I made my living as a model once upon a time.
用赚来的钱完成大学
I put myself through college.
我相信
I believe it.
我曾经…曾经做过兔女郎
I was a…I was even a Playmate once.
气得我父亲心脏病发
About gave my dad a heart attack.
- 什么？- 一九七四年 十月份
- What? - October 74?
可恶
Shit.
对
Yup.
噢 你们…
Uh, guys. Guys.
我的天 看着那
Oh, my God. Look at that.
混蛋热能追逐者
Goddamn little… heat seekers.
- 怎么样才对 爱尔？- 不要再问我
- What do we do, Earl? - You got to stop asking me.
- 我不知道 - 怎么了
- I don't know. - What's going on?
发生什么事？
What's happening?
不妙…狡猾的混蛋
Uh-oh. Smart little bastards. Whoa. Oh.
坏蛋来捉我吧 你肚子饿吗？
Come get me, you suckers. You hungry?
这里有近二百磅的瘦肉
A hundred and eighty-five pounds of lean meat.
你在作什么？
Burt, what are you doing?
这是你想要的
You know you want it.
毕
Burt. Burt.
他到底有什么病？
What is wrong with him?
他有否…想出个计划？
Has he got a plan?
毕常常有主意 通常来说
Burt's always got a plan… usually.
问题解决了
Problem solved.
做得好 你这疯子
Good. You maniac.
毕 你成功了 太好了
Who-oo. Oh, Burt, you did it.
你设了陷阱给那些丑东西
You tricked the little plug uglies.
蠢钝的感觉如何？
How's it feel to be so stupid?
- 我的天 他们找到东西吃 - 呃
- Oh, Christ. Did they find something to eat? - Uh.
里面有什么 姬？
What's in there, Kate?
我不知 有箱子 文具
I don't know… boxes, supplies.
甜…
Golosinas…
萨巴素
Dulce.
哥罗先那 夏宁娜…
Hell, uh… Dulce. Dulce.
- 阿罗丝… - 我知道
- Sweet. Golosinas… - I know this one. Snack.
甜的小吃？
Sweet snack food?
麦粉？
Rice flour.
我不知 我怎么知道？
I didn't know. How could I have had known?
我的天 它们还吃不够吗？
God. Don't they ever get tired of eating?
那差不多有一百只
There will be 100 of them.
好 好 我们去追捕它们
Okay, we're going to run for it.
什么？哪里？
What? Where?
我们不会成功的
We're not going to make it.
爱尔 对不起
Look. Earl, I am sorry.
很抱歉带给你这些
I am sorry I got you all into this.
来吧 加迪 我们还未死
Come on, Grady. We ain't dead yet.
好 快点 好 什么 什么 什么 好
Okay. Come on. Okay, what, what, what, what, okay?
我有个主意 刚想到的
Uh, I have got a plan. Sort of.
你们将这喷到我身上
You're going to squirt me with this.
很好 清水 那令你体温降低
That's great. CO2… It will make you cold.
对 它看不见我
Right. They won't see me.
你说谁？
Says who?
他们说得对
No, they're right.
这是可行的
It ought to work.
维持多久？
For how long?
至少我们要尝试
Well, we got to try something.
但目的呢？
But what is the point?
如果我能抵达你的货车
Look, if I can just get to your truck,
我就可以拿些炸药
I can grab some bombs.
爱尔 这样做太疯狂
Erl This is nuts.
是呀…同时…
Well, yeah, and…
让我去
Let me do it.
不要发神经 那是我的主意
Don't be stupid. It was my idea.
不 我令你身陷困境 是我错
No, I got you all into this. It's my fault.
- 我去货车 不得异议 - 快
- I am going in. Spray me. - come on
可恶 在他们出来前就要做
We got to do it before they break out.
现在就炸我吧 噢 上帝
Now, blast me. Okay. Oh, Jesus.
- 嗯 - 不好 石头割开纸
- Yes. - No. Rock rips through paper.
什么？
Oh
我去 把那衬衫给我
Huh. I go. Give me that shirt.
要有手套 这东西好冻
I need the gloves too. This stuff is cold.
你准备好吗？去吧
You ready? Here goes.
这东西好冻
Man, this stuff is cold.
好
Okay, here goes.
- 把我身后的门锁好 - 锁住它？
- Lock this door behind me. - Lock it?
是 我拿了炸药后
Yeah. I will get the bombs
会从另一道门走
and go out the other door.
好
All right.
看起来起作用了
Sounds like it's working.
我什么也看不见 在那处
I can't see anything. Over here.
这里
Here.
神圣的碎肉菜 好多呀
Holy tamole. There's dozens of them.
等一下 纸包石 不是吗？
Good Lord. Wait a minute. Paper wraps rock, doesn't it?
纸永远包住石
Paper always wraps rock.
可恶
Damn.
他开始溶解
He's starting to melt.
爱尔 你在溶化
Earl, you're melting.
快点 快点 去 去 去
Step on it. Come on. Go, go, go.
不好 它们看见他
Damn. They see him.
管子 我们需要管子或其他的
Uh… rope. We need rope or something.
在灭火筒旁有条防火喉
Hang on, Earl. A hose. There's a hose down by the fire hydrant.
快成功了
Here you go.
这太短
Ah. It's too short.
你听到吗？
Did you hear me?
防火喉太短 毕 赶快
The hose is too short. Burt, hurry.
- 我们走吧 快点 - 抓住 快
- Heads up, Earl. - Grab it. Come on.
走 快点 跑 走
Go. Run. Run. Go.
我装置了炸弹
I set a bomb.
什么？
What?
那是唯一我可想到的东西
It's the only thing I could think of.
姬 他做了什么 加迪？
Kate, what did he do? Grady? Come on.
那些炸药究竟在哪里？
Where the hell are the bombs?
我不知道…
I didn't have time.
我刚丢了一个在你的货车
I just threw one in your truck.
你做了什么？
You what?
那是两公吨半的极品炸药
That's two-and-a-half tons of high explosives.
你在说那些不足够？天
You saying that's not enough? God, Burt.
不要告诉我那不足够
Don't tell me it's not enough.
不够？那…
Not enough.
那…算了吧
Never mind. Never mind.
快点跑 加快点
Just run. Faster.
不 不 不 继续跑
No, no, no. Keep going.
那将会很大 极巨大
It's going to be big. Big.
他认真的吗？
Is he serious? Uh,
毕知道他炸药的威力
Burt knows his bombs.
那有多大？
How big can it be?
你按了多少时间？
How long did you set it for?
我不知道 我只按了一些键子
I don't know, I just pushed it.
天 那会很大 极巨大
God, it's going to be big. Big.
好吧 这会很好
All right, this will have to do.
躺下 掩着耳朵 那会很大
Get down. Stay down, cover your ears. It's going to be big.
一定要在今天吗？
Is it going to be today?
加迪 废话少说 躺下
Grady, get your ass down.
喂 加迪…你还好吗？
Hey, Grady. Grady. Grady, you all right, man?
你没事吧？
You okay?
谢谢
Yeah. Thanks.
自己小心
Oh. Watch yourselves.
加迪 有人认为我
You know, Grady. Some people
过份紧张…
think I am overprepared.
有精神病 甚至有些少疯颠
Paranoid. Maybe even a little crazy.
但那些人未接触过金拜恩生物
But they never met any Precambrian life forms, did they?
唔…看 呀…
Uh, look, uh…
我不介意留下
I don't mind hanging around down here for awhile.
你有空吗？
Going to have any free time?
你在这里数天就差不多被杀
Well, spend a couple days almost getting killed,
你要为自己的将来设想
you start thinking about your future.
还以为你要多点约会
Thinking you should date more?
是呀 不错
Well, yeah, actually.
喂 爱尔
Hey, Earl,
他们欠我们二十八只怪虫的酬金
I just realized they owe us for 28 worms, man.
那没错 我们没死
Hey, that's right. We didn't die.
虽然 我们几乎炸毁炼油厂
Although, we did kind of blow up their refinery.
那是我们工作的一部份
Hey, that's just part of the job.
事实上 那些小怪物还未计算
In fact, we ought to charge them for all those little ones too.
对 我们有足够的金钱
Oh, yeah. We will have enough
去建造我们的游乐场
to start our own theme park…
加迪和爱尔的怪兽天地
Grady and Earl's Monster World.
喂 休想
Hey, no way.
来吧 爱尔
Come on, Earl.
这是你第三次良机
This could be like your big, third chance.